We're almost at Mt. Mud Boat.
By the way, why are we here again?
Um...
This place always has
a lot of UFO sightings,
and most of them seem to happen around
the same time on New Year's Eve.
And this phenomenon apparently
occurs every seven years.
The last time there was
a sighting was seven years ago.
At least, that's what this article said.
Well, all this information
is rather convenient.
You've got this, Mob. We're almost there,
so don't go puking on me.
This road sure is something.
There's supposed to be
a hiking trail somewhere.
Huh?
What's wrong?
I think we passed the sign
for the hiking trail a ways back...
Uh, why didn't you mention that earlier?
I just thought he was trying to take us
as far as he could with the car.
"Licensed driver with little experience: I just thought
he was trying to take us as far as he could with the car.
"Licensed driver with little experience: 10 years" I just
thought he was trying to take us as far as he could with the car.
"Licensed driver with little experience:
10 years"
"Licensed driver with little
experience: 10 years" Ugh!
Ugh!
We're gonna have to go in reverse until
we find enough space to make a U-turn.
It's only 1:30 PM, so there's
probably no reason to hurry.
Yeah, says the guy who was an hour late.
Hey, let's calm down.
The UFO's not gonna come if we're too angry.
Huh? Are you mocking me?
And after I canceled my plans
for New Year's Eve to be here.
The hell'd you just say?
You were being all pouty,
so we were trying to be nice!
The hell's with that attitude?
N-Now, now...
Okay, time to put this baby in reverse.
M-Mob!
MOB MOB WOW! MOB MOB WOW!
I realized that my youth was grey
The root of this irritation is unknown
My brain runs parallel with this emotional train
Struggling adolescence
Don't disturb the subconscious mind
Who's that behind me?
Opposing ideas, distortion
Purge the sorrow
So, do what you can now.
My life
Finally
Break it down!!
(WANT) desire (YOUNG) and sincerity
(BURN) they begin to sprout (1) within my chest
(TRANCE) I won't awaken (CHANCE) but I want to
(STANCE) both sides of the coin
(1) are back-to-back
Accept me as I am
Conflicting freedom and relations
If they can become one
That smile will be
One and only "1"
MOB MOB WOW! MOB MOB WOW!
"Mob Psycho 100 III"
MOB MOB WOW!
One and only "1"
"Mob Psycho 100 III"
"Mob Psycho 100 "
MOB MOB WOW! MOB MOB WOW!
One and only "1"
"Transmission 2
- Encountering the Unknown~"
Are you okay?
Thank goodness. There's reception.
All right. Let's walk back
towards the hiking trail.
I'll come back to get the car later.
If we're going to walk, why don't we keep
going forward rather than go back?
Yeah, not happening.
Amateurs shouldn't walk the game trails
of mountains they're not familiar with.
I won't be able to take any responsibility
if something happens to you kids.
Um... Sorry, I'm gonna go take a piss.
Mob, you should go, too.
They don't seem to be coming back.
They aren't going number two, are they?
Did they get lost? I'll go take a look.
Hold it. It's dangerous to go alone.
We'll all go together.
--That way?
--No, it's that way.
Which way did we come from again?
We've definitely lost the path.
And now there's no reception.
Uh, we're probably gonna be
in trouble if it gets dark.
Sh-Should we head back down?
Whenever you get lost in the mountains,
I've heard that it's probably safer to head up
the mountain than try to go back down.
If we can get to a better vantage point,
we should be able to find a route.
Oh, I see.
I should've placed more obvious
markers along the way...
He sure seems knowledgeable,
even if he's an amateur.
Oh, crap! I left the book back in the car.
What? You're kidding.
The one that has the spell for
the UFO summoning ritual?!
It's no big deal.
Look, it's the mountain trail.
I think we might just make it
if we keep going!
Huh? Weren't we heading back?
We've come this far,
so let's actually summon a UFO!
Yeah, that's not happening.
We've been messing up left and right all day.
Seriously, Kurata...
Who do you think Inukawa and Saruta
painstakingly planned this all out for?
What? Really?
Are you seriously trying to
blame this on me right now?
I disbanded the Telepathy Club because
all of you never tried to do anything!
Today's no different.
I kept wondering if I should come or not!
Because I didn't want this
very thing to happen.
I only came because I believed you
when you said you found a telepathist.
And yet you had the nerve to lie to me...
None of you have any idea how I feel
getting my earnest hopes trampled on.
How could you?!
Anyway, there's really no point
in arguing right now,
so why don't we keep on walking?
No, I'm going home! I'm leaving!
I'm tired! I'm not climbing any farther!
I'll go back alone,
so all of you can keep on going.
Tome-san. Let's walk together.
Okay, fine. I just need
to keep walking, right?
All right, let's go.
Man, we're high up.
--We did it.
--4:19 PM...
We don't have much time
before the sun's gonna set.
Well... according to the documents,
the UFO usually appears around 5 PM,
so let's get ready to summon it.
Are we really doing this?
Didn't you forget the book in the car?
Prez, you were always reading that book.
You don't have the spell to
summon aliens memorized?
Of course I don't.
Isn't it enough that we all climbed
to the top of the mountain together?
We've already made
plenty of memories today.
This is a great view.
What are you doing, Takenaka?
Ahem...
Doofa stootoo ayaabagayari...
Prooha komo hipakaeeh...
After creating an "8" with the rocks
and setting a foot in either circle,
close your eyes and chant while facing
in the southwest direction...
Hands should look like this.
I know you remember this, Prez.
I got pretty serious researching all of this
and before I knew it, it was morning.
So... you weren't late because you
overslept from being too nervous?
This is way too embarrassing to even say.
The last thing I wanted to do was mess it up,
so I figured I'd do whatever I could.
You were that serious about this?
Yeah, I am.
I decided I'd help out because these three
were so serious about all this.
So could you believe us already?
But...
"Even then, I'm scared of this going wrong.
It's probably better to limit this
to chasing a fantasy.
Maybe all that matters in this
is whether we had fun.
Because my other memories
with everyone may all end up a joke, too.
We almost got lost in the mountains
because I'm forcing my delusions on them.
I don't want to face reality
any more than this." Apparently.
No way! We don't think
you're forcing your delusions on us.
This is something we wanted to do!
Before the Telepathy Club disbands.
Boys...
Then... Then you should've
just said so earlier!
Would it kill her to be honest?
If that's the case, we're all doing this.
Come on, start lining up those rocks.
Doofa stootoo ayaabagayari...
Prooha komo hipakaeeh...
--Prooha komo hipakaeeh...
--Master?
You said you researched this
all last night, right?
Are you sure you didn't
find out anything else?
Huh? Is your master
a telepathist, too?
No, I am not a telepathist...
...but I can read minds by observing
the subtle changes in your aura.
Apparently, he's the kind
of guy that's a total liar
but is good at reading people through
their actions and mannerisms.
Well, Takenaka?
Are you hiding anything else?
Well, the author of that occult book
was arrested two years ago for fraud.
The research in that book has no basis.
Even this ritual is completely fake.
Seriously?
So you're saying this is pointless?
What the hell?
I-I'm sorry I didn't tell you sooner.
I figured there was purpose in
the Telepathy Club working together, though.
And you're exactly right.
It's always worth it to do your best.
All of you ended up gathering
information and took action.
That's pretty impressive.
I'm sure this whole thing will always
be a precious memory of your youth.
It will always remain an important
experience in your hearts.
And you should be proud of that.
Y-You're right. We all did our best.
Y-Yeah.
There's no denying that
we actually did work hard.
I guess...
All right. It's getting pretty dark,
so let's head back.
What about the UFO sightings?
Were those also fake?
No, apparently those really happened.
I see.
Then let's do it.
We haven't tried everything yet.
Let's send out a telepathic message.
I'll give it my all, too,
so let's all try again.
Mob-kun...
Prez, do you want to try it?
--Let's do it.
--Yeah.
Come on, President Kurata.
Boys... Thank you.
Don't try moving too much.
Did you try too hard?
I-I'll be okay. But...
Dang it... I guess it didn't work.
Why all the long faces?
I-I mean...
Psychics and telepathists actually exist.
I'm sure we'll be able to communicate
with aliens someday!
Just look at how many stars are in the sky!
There's no reason to hurry.
I'm having plenty of fun being
with all of you, so it's fine.
Huh?
"Line up the rocks and
Doofa stootoo ayaabagayari!!"
"An Unidentified Flying
Object Actually Existed!"
Is this for real?
It actually came?
Wai-- Wh-Wh-What do we do?!
What am I supposed to do?!
Y-You're the one who wanted
to meet the aliens, Prez!
Y-Y-Yeah, b-but...
--Prez! Behind you! Behind you!
--S-Something's coming!
That was quick!
Uh, I... D-D-Do we have anything?!
Like a bug-catching net?
Why are you thinking about capturing them?!
Who knows what'll happen
if we make them mad?!
Th-This is what aliens look like?
Thin limbs...
Giant, developed heads...
Super-smooth skin...
Humongous, sparkly eyes...
There's no doubt about it.
They're the real deal!
They really do seem otherworldly...
I wonder if we can communicate with them.
They have really pretty eyes, though.
I don't sense any malice.
It seems like they want to shake hands...
Wait, with me? I-I'd be honored!
I can't believe I get to greet them
on behalf of Earth before anyone else!
Hey, I really wouldn't!
You never know what kind
of germs they're carrying.
Master...
Good for you, President Kurata.
Apparently, they want to show us
the inside of their spacecraft.
Really?!
Sweet! That's awesome!
Let's go, everyone!
A-Are you sure it's okay to get on?
I'll go, too.
In for a penny, in for a pound, I guess...
This really reminds me of our club room.
They're, like, super friendly.
I sorta figured they'd be kinda scary.
Prez, it's always been your dream to interact
with extraterrestrial lifeforms, right?
This is your chance to ask them all kinds
of things with Takenaka as your interpreter!
Yeah, I think I can make it work.
R-Right... Um... Uh...
I can't think of anything.
Oh, I know.
Why don't we play some games?
I always have this thing on me.
Nice! Let's show them how it works!
It's a new year...
All this is going on, yet all I can
think about is the turn of the year
and the late fees for the rental car...
They're blinding...
Whoa, it's almost morning.
We should head home soon.
You're right.
I, at least, told my parents I was spending
the night at a friend's house, but...
I mean, I guess we're all
friends now anyway.
All right, let's start wrapping things up.
I wonder if it's a gift.
It's so pretty.
It's a token of their
friendship, apparently.
They just keep staring.
Maybe we should give them
something in return?
Then I'll give them my scarf.
Um... Then I'll give them this notebook.
Here's my watch... It's pretty cheap, but...
You can have my gum.
Here's this gaming console from Earth.
Hm... I don't have anything.
Maybe I can show them some of my powers.
They seem pretty happy with that.
Oh, that's good.
Uh... Why are you stripping, Reigen-san?
I was in a hurry this morning,
so I'm still wearing my pajamas underneath.
You can have this.
They're very happy.
I guess anything goes.
Thank you so much for coming to see us.
Well, we'll be on our way now.
Let's meet again someday!
Hey, the first sunrise of the year.
I'll never forget today.
I'm sure everyone else feels
the same... I just know it.
Hey, wait.
Where's Inukawa?
New Year's Eve.
I was taken away by a UFO.
I'm going to try to convince them
to take me back to Earth.
But I'm dealing with aliens.
I can't communicate with them.
This is probably going to be
a long, drawn-out battle.
"New Year's Eve 201X I was taken away by a UFO. I can't communicate with them because they're aliens. They don't
seem to have any ill will, though. THEY DON'T, RIGHT?! This is probably going to be a long, drawn-out battle.
This is probably going to be
a long, drawn-out battle.
I'm sure this is all some sort of misunderstanding. THIS IS A MISUNDERSTANDING, RIGHT? Please let me go
back to Earth. I'm going to try to convince them. This is probably going to be a long, drawn-out battle.
I'm sure this is all some sort of misunderstanding. THIS IS A MISUNDERSTANDING,
RIGHT? Please let me go back to Earth. I'm going to try to convince them.
I'm sure this is all some sort of misunderstanding. THIS IS A MISUNDERSTANDING, RIGHT? Please let me go back to Earth.
I'm going to try to convince them. For now, I think I'm going to keep writing down my progress in this notebook.
For now, I think I'm going to keep writing
down my progress in this notebook.
But this is probably going to be a long, drawn-out battle. I think I'm going to keep writing down my
progress in this notebook.” For now, I think I'm going to keep writing down my progress in this notebook.
For now, I think I'm going to keep writing
down my progress in this notebook.
The next day, they all threw me
a welcome party...? Or something.
I had no idea what any of this stuff is,
but in the end, I chose something and ate it.
After that, my memories are a little foggy,
but I think something insane happened.
When I came to, I was in another
unfamiliar place, and my head was killing me.
That day, I realized just how much
a little bit of gaming time would mean to me.
But, more importantly, I wanted to go home.
The inhabitants of this planet
have a natural enemy.
It's a savage monster that
tries to eat all of their crops.
Despite being such an advanced race,
they'd never thought of using weapons.
And so, I took care
of that pest for them.
It ended up being about the size
of the dog I have back home.
It might be because I slew their monster,
but they treat me like a hero,
so life on this planet
isn't so bad after all.
I have no idea how much
time has passed now.
Everyone!
I have something
I need to tell you!
On the brink of loneliness, Inukawa was
able to link his thoughts with the aliens
and tell them that he wanted
to go back home to Earth.
If you have something you want to say,
just look them in the eyes
and you'll be able to get
through to them.
Inukawa realized this, but by
the time he got back to Earth,
most of his memories had
become fuzzy and vague.
English Translator: Michelle Tymon Translation Editor: Zachary Carlysle Translation
Checker: Sriram Gurunathan most of his memories had become fuzzy and vague.
Most of his memories had
become fuzzy and vague.
What? You're joking, right?
What? Really?
Tsubomi-chan is... transferring?
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 Il Episode 9:
"Mob 1
- Moving~."
"Mob 1 - Moving~"
"Mob 1 - Moving~."
"Mob 1
- Moving~"